Arturo, son. Hurry, I have to get going.
"پسرم "آرتورو عجله کن، من بايد برم
- How many are left? - Three.
چند تا مونده؟ - سه تا -
Lau, hurry, sweetie. I'm gonna be late.
.لائو"، عجله کن عزيزم" .داره ديرم ميشه
They're ready.
.آماده شدن
Dad, I've decided to go for it.
.بابا من تصميم گرفتم براي بدست آوردنش تلاش کنم
I don't think I want you to go.
.من راضي نيستم بري
Come on, Dad. I've always been responsible. I won't let you down.
.يالا بابا. من هميشه مسئوليت پذير بودم .نا اُميدت نميکنم
I'm not sure. I just don't like that environment for you.
مطمئن نيستم. من صلاح نميدونم .بري تو اون محيط
Have some faith in me, Dad.
بهم ايمان داشته باش بابا
Little man, come here.
.مردِ کوچولو، بيا اينجا
You're gonna have to get to school on your own today.
.امروز خودت بايد تنهايي بري مدرسه
When you get back, lock yourself in.
وقتي برگشتي خونه .در رو قفل کن
Where are you going?
کجا داري ميري؟
I'll see you tonight.
.امشب ميبينمت
What time will you be back?
کي برميگردي؟
Late!
!دير وقت
Lau! Lau!
!"لائو"! "لائو"
Girl, what are you doing there? I've been looking for you.
دختر، اينجا داري چيکار ميکني؟ .داشتم دنبالت ميگشتم
And what's with those rags? Where's your dress?
و اين لباسهاي کهنه چيه آخه؟ پس لباست کو؟
Let's go. Hurry, the line is super long.
.بريم. عجله کن .صف بينهايت طولانيه
Do you know what the grand prize will be?
اصن ميدوني جايزه بزرگ رقابتها چيه؟
What are you talking about? What fucking prize?
درباره چي داري حرف ميزني؟ چه جايزه کوفتي اي؟
- For the winner! - What winner?
!جايزه نفر اول ديگه - چه نفرِ اولي؟ -
The pageant, girl. Do you know what she gets?
.برنده نمايش، دختر ميدوني چي گيرِ اون اومدش؟
No, what?
نه، چي؟
She has to have sex with one of those old, rich guys.
بايد با يکي از اون .آدم پولدارا همبستر بشه
Where do you come up with that kind of crap? Come on, let's go.
اين مزخرفات رو از کجات در مياري؟ يالا، بريم
Your entry forms?
فُرم هاي وروديت؟
I spoke to Luisa. She wanted to see my friend.
.من با "لوئيزا" حرف زدم .ميخواست دوستِ منو ببينه
- Name and phone number? - Laura Guerrero.
اسم و شماره تلفنتون؟ - "لورا گوئررو" -
- Phone number? - 638-3279.
شماره تلفن؟ - 638-3279 -
I'm not sure you can go in. You're very late.
.مطمئن نيستم بتوني بري تو .چونکه خيلي دير اومدي
No, wait. I was here earlier. Someone's holding my place in line.
.نه، واسا. من خيلي زودتر اومدم .يه نفر جام صف واساده بود
Hey, you can't cut in line. What's your problem?
.هي، نميتوني بدون صف بري تو مشکلت چيه؟
Chill, girl. Someone's holding my place in line.
.آروم باش، دختر .يه نفر جام صف واساده بود
You can't cut, you bitch.
.نميتوني بي صف بري تو عوضي
Oh, whatever, calm down. I was already here, don't get crazy.
.اُه، بگذريم، آروم باش .من اينجا بودم، بيخود شلوغش نکن
- Stand in line like everyone else. - Calm down. Just drop it.
.مثه بقيه واسا تو صف - .آروم باش. فقط بيخيال شو -
- You can't cut! - Calm down.
!نميتوني بي صف بري .آروم باش -
- Get back there... - Suzu.
...برگرد همونجا - "سوزو" -
- Do you want in or not? - Yes.
ميخواي وارد مسابقه بشي يا نه؟ - بله -
Okay, where's your dress?
خيلي خب، لباست کو پس؟
You're supposed to be wearing it.
.بايد اونو بپوشي
Go get changed. Quickly.
.برو لباستو عوض کن .سريع
- Do you see that line on the floor? - Yes.
اون خطِ روي زمين رو ميبيني؟ - آره -
Walk it.
.همونو بگير بيا
As you're walking out, smile, tell me your name, age...
،و همونجوري هم که داري ميري ...لبخند بزن، اسمت رو بهم بگو بعلاوه سنت
...and say, "My dream is to represent the beautiful women of my state."
و بگو " روياي من اينه که ".بعنوان دخترِ زيباي استانم انتخاب بشم
Got it?
فهميدي؟
Okay. Hurry up, sweetie.
.خيلي خب، عجله کن عزيزم
Come on.
.يالا
My name is Laura Guerrero, I'm 23 years old...
"اسمِ من "لورا گوئررو ...23 سالمه
...and my dream is to represent the beautiful women of my state.
و روياي من اينه که بعنوانِ .دخترِ زيباي استانم انتخاب بشم
Don't laugh.
.نخند
Let me see your nails.
.بزار ناخنات رو ببينم
Oh, you have to fix them. They look like my maid's nails.
.اُه، بايد درستشون کني .مثه ناخنهاي خدمتکارم ميمونن
Fine, you're in.
.خوبه، تو قبولي
I want to see you both tomorrow, very early. Seven o'clock a.m., ready to rehearse.
.ميخوام که فردا صبحِ زود، هر دوتون رو ببينم .ساعت 7 صبح، آماده تمرين
You got it. Thanks.
.فهميدم. مرسي
Thanks.
.مرسي
- For those of us who are fair-skinned. - Oh, be quiet, blondie.
براي ماهايي که پوستِ لطيفي داريم - .اُه ساکت شو، مو طلايي -
Look at this dress, it's great.
.اين لباس رو نيگا کن. عاليه
I just saw this other one, it's prettier.
.اين يکي رو هم ديدم، قشنگتره
- What do you think? - Wait.
نظر تو چيه؟ - .صبر کن -
- Lau. - Hold on, I wanna watch this.
"لائو" - .واسا، بايد اينو ببينم -
Why do you care what that girl does? Pay attention. Lau.
واست چه اهميتي داره که اون دخترِ چيکار کرده؟ "خوب گوش کن. "لاو
You're going to like this one. Lau.
"تو هم قراره مثه اون بشي "لائو
Fucking Javi is here.
.ژاوي" لعنتي اينجاست"
- I've gotta go. - What's that guy doing here?
.بايد برم - اون يارو اينجا چيکار ميکنه؟ -
- He wants to go to the Millennium Club. - Thought we were going shopping.
"ميخواد بره به کلوبِ "ملنيوم - .فکر ميکنه ما رفتيم خريد -
- What do you want me to do? - Tell him you'll see him later.
ميخواي من چيکار کنم؟ - .بهش بگو که بعدا ميبينيش -
Girl.
.دختر
Fine. Wait for me here.
.خوبه. همينجا منتظرم بمون
Let me go tell him.
.بزار برم بهش بگم
What's up, babe?
چه خبر، جيگر؟
What the hell are you doing here? Come on, let's go.
اينجا چه غلطي ميکني؟ .يالا، بيا بريم
I'll pay you later.
.بعدا پولت رو ميدم
I'm with Suzu, I think she's with Javi.
.من با "سوزو" هستم. فک کنم اون با "ژاوي" ــه
Go ahead.
.بفرما
Let her through. She's with Javi.
.بزارين رد شه. اون با "ژاوي"ــه
Suzu, what happened? Why did you leave?
سوزو" چي شده؟" چرا رفتي پس؟
I've been looking for you.
.داشتم دنبالِ تو ميگشتم
Get over here.
.بيا اينجا
Hey, hey! Don't touch her like that, asshole!
هي، هي! اونجوري به اون !دست نزن عن آقا
What the fuck is wrong with you?
تو چه مرگت شده؟
Let me go.
.ولم کن
Okay, asshole, stop!
!خيلي خب عوضي، بس کن
She's leaving, I'll take her out.
.اون داره ميره. من از اينجا ميبرمش
Don't come back. She needs a fucking shower.
.ديگه برنگرد اون حتما يه حمومي بايد بره
I'm sorry, Lau.
"معذرت ميخوام "لائو
Lau, these guys have connections. They can help us win the contest.
.لائو" اين آدما پارتي هاي کلفتي دارن" .ميتونن کمکمون کنن مسابقه رو ببريم
What kind of connections are these assholes going to have?
چه ارتباطاتي اين عوضي ها ممکنِ داشته باشن آخه؟
Lau.
"لائو"
If you want me to, I'll tell Javi we're leaving.
اگه تو ازم بخواي به .ژاوي" ميگم که داريم ميريم"
And we can go somewhere else.
.و ميتونيم بريم يه جاي ديگه
Let's go. I'll meet you out front.
.بريم. اون بيرون ميبينمت
Wait for me at the door.
.جلوي در منتظرم بمون
Let's move.
.تکون بخورين
Do you recognize me?
منو ميشناسي يا نه؟
Pick it up.
.بَرِش دار
How many people are out there?
چند نفر اون بيرونن؟
I don't know.
.نميدونم
Okay, get out of here.
.خيلي خب، برو بيرون
Keep your mouth shut.
.خفه خون ميگيريا
We're ready. Everybody take their positions.
.ما آماده ايم .همه در موقعيت خودشون قرار بگيرن
Stay calm.
.خونسردي خودت رو حفظ کن
Nothing's going on here.
.هيچ اتفاقي اينجا نميوفته
No mercy, boss. No mercy.
.رحم نکن رئيس .بخششي در کار نيست
Suzu, let's get out of here!
!سوزو" بيا از اينجا بريم"
Everybody on the floor!
!همه بخوابن رو زمين
Suzu!
!"سوزو"
- On the floor! - Suzu!
!بخوابين رو زمين - "سوزو" -
Get him! Get him! Don't move!
!بگيرش! بگيرش! تکون نخور
Get those pigs! Get them!
!اون خوکها رو بگير! بگيرنشون
Come on, come on, hurry!
!يالا، زود باش، عجله کن
Get the job done! Hurry, hurry!
!برو کارتو تموم کن! يالا، يالا
Find the American!
!آمريکاييِ رو پيدا کنين
Gather the bodies. Come on! Put them together.
.اجساد رو جمع کن .زود باش! بزارشون کنار هم
- The cops are on their way. - Okay, boss, ready.
.پليسا تو راهن - خيلي خب، رئيس. آماده -
Ventura, bring the truck, hurry!
!ونتورا" وانت رو بيار، زود باش"
Parca, bring the other trucks out back.
.پارکا" بقيه وانتها رو بيار اون پشت"
Come on, come on, let's go. Time's up!
.يالا، يالا، بريم !وقتمون تموم شده
The pigs are on their way.
.اون خوکها (پليسا) تو راهن
Hurry, let's go. We're out of time!
!يالا، بريم. وقتمون داره تموم ميشه
We're done. Over. Let's go.
.کارمون تمومه. تمام. بريم
Hop on, hurry!
!بِپَر بريم، زود باش
They're getting closer, move it!
!دارن نزديکتر ميشن، تکون بخور
Leave the rest of the bodies, let's go!
!بقيه اجساد رو بزار بمونه، بريم
Fucking hurry! They're here, let's go!
!اَلدنگ عجله کن! اونا رسيدن، بريم
Let's go!
!بريم
Officer, my friend's inside! Please let me in!
!سرکار، دوستِ من داخله !بزارين منم برم داخل
There's nobody inside. You have to go!
.هيشکي اون داخل نيست !بايد از اينجا بري
Ma'am.
.خانُم
Have you heard anything?
خبري نشدش؟
Me either.
.منم همينطور
Yes, I'll let you know.
.بله، خبرتون ميکنم
Thanks.
.مرسي
What do you mean, she didn't make it?
منظورت چيه که نتونست بياد؟
You're out. We're rehearsing. We looked everywhere.
.تو خط خوردي. داشتيم تمرين ميکرديم .همه جا رو گشتيم
We got into some trouble.
.تو دردسر افتاده بوديم
- I don't know what else to say, you're out. - It's not fair.
.نميدونم چي بايد بگم. تو خط خوردي - .اين منصفانه نيست -
Look, sweetie, nothing's fair.
.ببين عزيزم، هيچي عادلانه نيست
Take this as a lesson. You have to be more responsible. Goodbye.
اينو بعنوان يه درس بفهم. بايد .بيشتر مسئوليت پذير باشي. خداحافظ
I'm sorry, Luisa.
."متاسفم "لوئيزا
Give me another chance.
.بهم يه فرصتِ ديگه بده
Let me find her and we'll come back, please.
بزار پيداش کنم .و بعدش برميگرديم، خواهش ميکنم
Just leave.
.فقط برو
Okay, ready, girls? From the top.
خيلي خب، آماده اين، دخترا؟ .از اول شروع ميکنيم
- I need your help. - What's going on?
.به کمکت احتياج دارم - چي شده؟ -
I can't find my friend.
.نميتونم دوستم رو پيدا کنم
- Where did you leave her? - We were at the Millennium nightclub.
کجا گُمش کردي؟ - .ما تو کلوبِ "ملنيوم" بوديم -
- When? Last night? - Yes.
کي؟ ديشب؟ - اره -
I do transit only. I can't help you. Go to the police station.
.من فقط يه راننده ام. نميتونم کمکت کنم .برو پاسگاهِ پليس
No, wait, can you please try to find her using your radio?
نه، صبر کن، ميتونم ازت خواهش کنم از طريقِ بيسيمت پيداش کني؟
- Name? - Mine?
اسم؟ - اسمِ من؟ -
- No, your friend's name. - Azucena Ramos.
.نه بابا، اسمِ دوستت - "آزوسِنا راموس" -
No, you have to go to the police station.
.نه، بايد بري پاسگاهِ پليس
Come on, help me. Please.
.بيخيال، کمکم کن. خواهش ميکنم
Fine. Get in, quickly.
.خيلي خب. زود سوار شو
Tell me what happened.
.بهم بگو چه اتفاقي افتاد
We were just hanging out...
...داشتيم سگ چرخ ميزديم
...and these people came.
.و يه دفعه يه آدمايي اومدن
- And then? - They had guns...
و بعدش؟ - ...اونا اسلحه داشتن -
...and they started shooting.
.و بعدش شروع کردن تيراندازي...
I think they took some people in plastic bags.
فک ميکنم چند نفري رو هم .تو کيسه هاي پلاستيکي کردن بُردن
- Wait a sec. - I was scared.
.يه لحظه دندون رو جيگر بزار - .من ترسيده بودم -
Okay, give me a sec.
.خيلي خب، صبر کن چند لحظه
R-12, do you copy? R-12.
"آر-12" صدامو ميشنوي؟ "آر-12"
- Copy. - I have a 38 on my hands.
.دريافت شد - .يه موردِ 38 بهم برخورده -
She claims she was at yesterday's incident, at the Millennium.
ادعا ميکنه که در واقعه ديروز .در کلوبِ "ملنيوم" حضور داشته
I'll get right back to you. Let me check with R-1.
.بهت خبر ميدم .بزار با "آر-1" بررسيش کنم
Yes, please. Check on it and call me back. Thanks.
باشه، لطفا بررسي کنيد .و باهام تماس بگيريد. مرسي
What were you doing there?
اونجا چيکار ميکردي؟
Wait.
.صبر کن
Hello.
.سلام
Yes.
.بله
Correct.
.صحيح
I'm on my way.
.همين الان ميام اونجا
Where are we going?
کجا داريم ميريم؟
We're going just up ahead to the station. They'll take down your statement.
.داريم ميريم سمتِ پاسگاه .ميخوان اظهاراتت رو ثبت کنن
I want you to testify about everything you saw and heard.
ازت ميخوام درباره همه .چيزايي که ديدي و شنيدي شهادت بدي
What else did you see or hear?
ديگه چيا شنيدي يا ديدي؟
It was very dark.
.تاريک بودش
What's your name?
اسمت چيه؟
Laura.
"لورا"
Laura what?
لورا" چي؟"
Laura Guerrero.
"لورا گوئررو"
Don't worry, Laura.
"نگران نباش "لورا
Wait right here.
.همينجا منتظر بمون
I'll be back.
.الان برميگردم
Don't move, I'm grabbing my lunch.
.تکون نخور، ميخوام ناهارم رو بگيرم
What are you looking for?
دنبال چي ميگردي؟
I'm looking for my friend.
.دنبالِ دوستم ميگردم
What friend?
چه دوستي؟
- She was with me at the Millennium. - Check her out, make sure she's clean.
.اونم باهام تو کلوب بودش - .بازرسيش کن، مطمئن شو که پاکِ پاکه -
Sir, wait, what's going on?
قربان، صبر کنين، چه خبره؟
Boss, that skinny chick from the Millennium is here.
.رئيس اون دافِ لاغرِ کلوب "ملنيوم" اينجاس
No.
.نه
Get over here. Get out.
.بيا اينجا. بيا
- Sir, please, wait. - Open the door.
.قربان خواهش ميکنم. صبر کنين - .در رو وا کن -
No!
!نه
- Get her inside! - Let me go!
!بندازش اون تو - !ولم کنين -
Get her inside!
!بندازش اون تو
No!
!نه
Linito, we're on our way.
.لينيتو" ما تو راهيم"
- Who sent you? - Nobody, I came here on my own.
کي تو رو فرستاده؟ - .هيشکي، خودم اومدم اينجا -
What does she want?
چي ميخوادش؟
- What the fuck are you looking for? - Sorry, I made a mistake.
دنبالِ چي داري ميگردي؟ - .معذرت ميخوام، اشتباه کردم -
- Let me go. - She's clean, boss.
.ولم کنين - .اون پاکه رئيس -
I swear I won't say a word.
.قسم ميخورم که حرفي نزنم
- Sure it's the girl from yesterday? - Yeah, from the bathroom.
مطمئني همون دختر ديروزي اس؟ - .آره، تو دستشويي ديدمش -
She came with Toñito, looking for her friend.
.با "تويتو" اومده بود .دنبالِ دوستش ميگرده
- What the fuck are you looking for? - Go ahead. You know what to do.
دنبالِ چي داري ميگردي؟ - .ادامه بده. خودت ميدوني بايد چيکار کني -
I'm sorry, sir. I made a mistake, please let me go.
.معذرت ميخوام آقا .غلط کردم، ولم کنين
If I catch you lying, I'll beat the shit out of you.
اگه بفهمم داري دروغ ميگي .ميزنم دهنت رو سرويس ميکنم
What's your name?
اسمت چيه؟
Laura Guerrero, sir.
.لورا گوئررو" اقا"
Where do you live?
کجا زندگي ميکني؟
915 Angela Peralta.
"خيابون "915 آنجلا پرالتا
Phone number?
شماره تلفن؟
638-3279.
638-3279
Who do you live with?
با کي زندگي ميکني؟
With my dad and my brother.
.با بابام و داداشم
What do you do for a living?
شغلت چيه؟
We sell clothes.
.لباسفروشي داريم
What were you looking for?
دنبال چي ميگشتي؟
I went looking for my friend Suzu after fighting with the people from the pageant.
داشتم دنبال دوستم "سوزو" ميگشتم .بعدِ اينکه با مسئولاي برنامه دعواش شده بود
What pageant?
کدوم نمايش؟
Miss Baja.
"دختر شايسته ايالت باخا"
Okay, Canelita.
."خيلي خب "کانليتا (در زبان اسپانيولي نامي است به معناي مهربان)
Listen, Canelita.
."گوش کن "کانليتا
Stay calm.
.آروم باش
Okay, Canelita. I'm gonna help you.
."خيلي خب، "کانليتا .من بهت کمک ميکنم
But I need you to do something for me.
اما تو هم بايد واسه من .يه کاري بکني
What do you say?
نظرت چيه؟
Do you know how to drive?
رانندگي بلدي؟
Well?
خوبه؟
Cali.
"کالي"
Gather the crew.
.افراد رو جمع کن
Okay, they're on their way.
.خيلي خب، اونا تو راهن
Hide.
.قايم شو
Canelita, here are the keys.
.کانليتا" کليدا اينجان"
Stay down for a bit. I'll be waiting for you outside, okay?
.يه مدتي همين پايين بمون بعدش من بيرون منتظرتم،باشه؟
Let's go. Hurry, hurry.
.بريم. يالا، يالا
Follow us, park where I tell you and wait for us on the other side.
دنبالِ ما بيا، هر جايي که بهت گفتم .ماشينو پارک کن و اونور خيابون منتظر ما بمون
Hey, lady, get out of here.
.هي، خانوم، از اينجا برو
Get her in, get her in!
!بيارينش داخل، بيارش تو
- Block the street! - Don't let anybody through. Get her inside.
!خيابون رو ببندين - اجازه ندين هيشکي عبور کنه. بيارش داخل -
- Cali, stand watch! - Let's go! Don't let anybody else through.
!کالي" مراقب باش" - .بريم! نزار هيشکي رد بشه -
Nobody else goes through!
!هيشکي ديگه رد نشه
Let's go, hurry!
!بريم، عجله کن
Clear out! Clear out! Let's move.
!همه چي رو جمع کنين !بار و بَنديل رو ببندين! بريم
Come and get it, pigs.
.بياين جلو خوکها
Lino, we're clearing out. Go down the main boulevard...
.لينو" همه چيو جمع کرديم" ...برين سمتِ پايينِ بلوار
You smoked them, Canelita.
"تو باعث شدي زود کارمون تموم بشه "کانليتا
Hey, man, see who's in charge of that beauty queen thing.
هي، مَرد، ببين مسئولِ .اون مراسمِ انتخاب ملکه زيبايي کيه
We're gonna help her get in.
ميخوايم اين خانُم رو کمک کنيم .وارد مسابقه شه
How does that sound, Canelita?
نظرت چيه "کانليتا"؟
Come on, smile.
.يالا، بخند
The pigs are on Juarez Street.
.پليسا تو خيابون "خوارز" هستن
Keep your eyes open, stand guard.
چشاتون رو خوب وا کنين .و مراقب باشين
They're goners, they left.
،اونا دارن رَد ميشن .دارن ميرن
Keep going, we're clear.
.ادامه بدين، اوضاع خوبه
What does a miss do, aside from sitting on her ass all day?
يه دوشيزه جز اينکه در طول روز فقط بشينه رو يه صندلي ديگه چيکارا ميکنه؟
She makes money.
.پول هم در مياره
What if I do get you in?
اگه واردِ مسابقه کنمت چي؟
Those on the right are with us, they'll let you through.
اون افراد سمتِ راست با ما هستن .ميزارن رَد بشين
Any news on my friend?
خبري از دوستم نشد؟
Okay, we're going straight.
.خيلي خب، ما داريم مستقيم حرکت ميکنيم
I'm working on it. Give me time.
.دارم روش کار ميکنم. مهلت بهم بده
Keep going straight, cross Defensores.
همينجوري مستقيم برو .تقاطع "دِفِنسورِس" رو هم رَد کن
You got it. We're headed that way.
.فهميدم. ما تو همون مسيريم
Through Anzures, do you copy?
آنزورس" رو رد کن، فهميدي؟"
Copy. We got a green light. Let's move, let's go.
.دريافت شد. ما چراغ سبز داريم .بريم، بريم
Keep going straight. It's clear.
.مستقيم بريد همچنان. امنه
Those on Serdan Street are with us.
اونايي که تو خيابون "سِردان" هستن .با ما هستن
I'll let you know when we move again.
وقتي دوباره حرکت کرديم .خبرت ميکنم
We're staying here for now.
.فعلا اينجا ميمونيم
Laura, we made a mistake.
.لورا" ما يه اشتباهي کرديم"
I've signed you up. Here's your number.
.من ثبتِ نامت کردم. اينم شماره اته
And Suzu?
و "سوزو" چي؟
We're waiting for her.
.منتظرِش ميمونيم
I need you to fill in some info.
.ازت ميخوام فرم اطلاعات رو پُر کني
You're in, Canelita.
"تو هم تو مسابقه هستي "کانليتا
In a little while, they'll bring your friend to you.
در همين حين هم .اونا دوستت رو ميارن پيشت
Buy yourself the nicest dress you can find.
واسه خودت خوشکلترين .لباسي که ميتوني رو بخر
Parca here will drive you. And later, you go to the hideout.
.پارکا" واست رانندگي ميکنه" .و بعدش هم برو به مخفيگاه
No, thanks.
.نه، مرسي
I'm not asking you.
.ازت درخواست نکردم که
She was on the phone with someone.
.اون با يکي داشته تلفني حرف ميزده
Give me your phone.
.تلفنت رو بده بهم
Who did you call?
به کي زنگ زدي؟
I sent a message to my friend.
.يه پيامک به دوستم فرستادم
I told you I was taking care of that.
.بهت گفتم که من ترتيبِ اونو ميدم
I don't want you using your phone.
.نميخوام که از تلفنت استفاده کني
Give me another one.
.بهم يکي ديگه بده
How long has it been since we used this one?
چه مدتِ که داريم از اين يکي استفاده ميکنيم؟
This one is old, it's clean.
.اين يکي قديمه و خطش امنه
I want you to take her to buy a dress. Then take her to the hideout.
.ازت ميخوام که با خودت ببريش تا لباس بخره .بعدش هم ببرش به مخفيگاه
You got it, boss.
.بروي چشم رئيس
I'll call you later.
.بعدا بهت زنگ ميزنم
Okay?
باشه؟
- Is there another exit? - Where are you going?
اينجا درِ خروجي ديگه اي هم داره؟ - کجا داري ميري؟ -
Sorry. Thanks.
.معذرت ميخوام. مرسي
Can I help you with something?
ميتونم کمکتون کنم؟
Hello.
.سلام
I'm looking for a dress.
دارم دنبال يه لباس ميگردم
What's the occasion?
براي چه مناسبتي؟
For a beauty pageant.
.براي مراسم انتخاب دختر زيبا
In our store, all of the dresses are custom-made.
در فروشگاهِ ما، همه لباسها .سفارشي دوخته ميشن
You won't find anything under $1000.
.لباس زيرِ 1000 دلار پيدا نميکنيد
Yeah, I have the money.
.باشه، پولش رو دارم
Here is the green one you liked.
اينجا يه لباس سبز رنگ .که شما ازش خوشتون مياد رو دارم
- Thanks. - Let me know if you need anything else.
.مرسي - .اگه چيز ديگه اي احتياج داشتين خبرم کنين -
Yes?
بله؟
Canelita, where are you?
کانليتا" کجايي تو؟"
Here.
.اينجا
Here, where?
اينجا کجاس؟
Everything okay? Do you need help?
همه چي مرتبه؟ کمک نميخواي؟
I'm sorry.
.معذرت ميخوام
Go home.
.برو خونه
Where were you?
کجا بودي؟
- Where's Dad? - In his room.
بابا کجاس؟ - .تو اتاقش -
Where did you sleep?
کجا خوابيده بودي؟ -
With Suzu. Be quiet.
.با "سوزو" . ساکت باش
- Cover for me? - Yes.
هوامو داري؟ - .آره -
Open up.
.بازش کن
What's going on?
چه خبره؟
What's wrong, Lau?
چي شده "لائو"؟
Nothing.
.هيچي
Are you okay?
حالت خوبه؟
Yes.
.آره
Why did you go away?
چرا رفته بودي؟
Also, during the operation...
...همچنين در اين عمليات
... two members of the criminal group La Estrella were captured.
دو عضو گروهِ خلافکارِ... .لا اِسترلا" بازداشت شدند"
- Can you bring me something to eat? - Yes.
يه چيزي واسم مياري بخورم؟ - .آره -
- Alias Lino, was able to escape, his whereabouts...
..با نام مستعارِ "لينو" موفق به فرار از محل شد -
Little man, don't make noise.
.مرد کوچک، سر و صدا نکن
This is yet another run-in between the police and this criminal group...
اين دستگيري و کشمکشِ ديگري ...مابينِ پليس و اين گروه خلافکار است
... that started after they were identified as being responsible for leaving a vehicle...
که پس از آن انجام شد که آنها... ...مسئولِ رها کردن يک ماشين
... in front of the embassy containing the bodies of an agent...
روبروي سفارت که شاملِ... ...اجسادِ يک مامور
... a federal police officer and a young woman, not yet identified.
پليسِ فدرال آمريکا و... .البته يک زنِ جوان است که هنوز شناسايي نشده
It has been General Salomón Duarte's primary agenda...
"از زمان انتصاب ِ ژنرال "سالومن دوارتس
... after being named chief of police for the state...
بعنوانِ رئيس پليسِ... ... ايالت
... to combat the various criminal groups that are taking over the state of Baja California.
"مبارزه با گروه هاي خلافکار که در ايالتِ "باخا کاليفرنيا... .فعاليت ميکنند در دستور کار قرار گرفته است
Lino is thought to be one of the most active criminals in this state.
تصور ميگردد "لينو" يکي از فعالترين .مجرمان اين ايالت باشد
He is suspected of being responsible for a recent attack in the Millennium nightclub...
او همچنين مظنون به دست داشتن ...در حمله اخير به کلوبِ شبانه "ملنيوم" است
... where the lives of 12 officers and civilians were lost.
که منجر به مرگ 12 افسر پليس و... .شهروندان شد
Did you go to school?
مدرسه رفتي؟
No.
.نه
- Why not? - He didn't take me.
چرا؟ - .بابا منو نبُرد -
What have you been doing?
داشتي چيکار ميکردي؟
Nothing.
.علاف
What's that?
اون چيه؟
It's all I could find.
.همه چيزيِ که تونستم پيدا کنم
Thanks.
.مرسي
What happened to you?
چه اتفاقي واست افتاده؟
I fell down.
.خوردم زمين
Ouch, it hurts!
!آخ، درد داره ها
Don't laugh.
.نخند
Arturo, get dressed.
.آرتورو" لباس بپوش"
Open the door, fucker!
!در رو وا کن، لعنتي
Step back.
.عقب واسا
- Step back, motherfucker. - Take anything you want.
.عقب واسا مادر سگ - .هر چي که ميخواي رو بردار -
- Where is Laura, motherfucker? - Who is Laura?
لورا" کجاست مادر سگ؟" - لورا" کيه؟" -
Do you want to die?
ميخواي بميري؟
Dad.
.بابا
I'm gonna fucking kill you. I know she's here.
.ميزنم بدجور ميکُشمت .ميدونم که اينجاس
You son of a bitch, where is she?
پدر سوخته، اون کجاس؟
There's no one here, man.
.هيشکي اينجا نيس مَرد
Dad.
.بابا
Go to your room.
.برو تو اتاقت
Go on!
!برو
Turn off all the lights.
.چراغا رو خاموش کن
Nobody goes near the windows.
.هيشکي نزديک پنجره ها نشه
Wait, please.
.صبر کن، خواهش ميکنم
Come on!
!يالا
Arturo!
!"آرتورو"
Come with me.
.باهام بيا
Don't look back, okay?
عقب رو نگاه نکن، باشه؟
Stay in here.
.همينجا بمون
Everything is going to be okay.
.همه چي درست ميشه
Goddamn it.
.لعنتي
Why the fuck did you run away?
چرا فرار کردي؟
Do you see what happened? Fucking shit.
ديدي چه اتفاقي افتاد؟ .لعنتي
Who the fuck took your phone?
کي گوشيت رو برداشت؟
I don't know.
.نميدونم
Go to your room.
.برو تو اتاقت
How many of them were there?
چند تا پليس اونجا بود؟
Like six or seven.
.شش، هفت تايي ميشد
What kind of trucks did they have?
چجور ماشينهايي داشتن؟
Black ones.
.از اين سياه ها
What did they do to you?
باهات چيکار کردن؟
They hit me and took the phone.
.کتکم زدن و تلفنم رو گرفتن
- What else? - Nothing.
ديگه چي؟ - .هيچي -
Move over.
.برو اونور
Cover that lamp.
.لامپ رو خاموش کن
- Linito, where you at? - Copy.
لينيتو" کجايي؟" - .دريافت شد -
They took all our ammo.
.همه مهماتِ ما رو گرفتن
They also got Ventura.
.وِنتورا" رو هم همينطور"
We had to run. They took over our hideout.
.بايد فرار کنيم .پناهگاهمون رو هم تسخير کردن
Who the fuck did you go see?
ميخواستي بري کدوم خري رو ببيني؟
Nobody.
.هيشکي رو
Then why the fuck did you run away?
پس چرا فرار کردي؟
Roquita. I'm in the clear.
.روکوئيتا" من جام امنه"
Everything is calm on this side.
.همه چي اينور آرومه
Got it.
.فهميدم
Cut the radios and start calling the U.S.
تماسهاي راديويي رو قطع کن .و به آمريکا زنگ بزن
All right, boss. We're fearless.
.خيلي خب رئيس. ما شجاعيم
I need you to run an errand for me.
.ميخوام يه پيغامي رو واسم برسوني
Did you hear me?
شنيدي چي گفتم؟
Anything you want.
.هر چي که تو بخواي
Just let my brother go.
.فقط بزار برادرم بره
You've got a deal.
پس يه معامله اي ميکنيم
We're in the clear.
ما جامون امنه
Jimmy, Jimmy.
."جيمي"، "جيمي"
We want three boxes.
.سه جعبه ميخوايم
Ramón, open up.
.رامون" باز کن"
I've packed up some things for you.
يه سري وسايل رو واستون ميزارم تو ساک
Don't say anything.
.هيچي نگو
If something happens, I'm going to pay for it.
اگه اتفاقي افتاد خودم تقاصش رو پس ميدم
Wait, you go. Tell them I'll stay in your place.
.صبر کن، تو برو .بهشون بگو منو به جات نگه دارن
We can't do that.
.نميتونيم اينکارو کنيم
Take this.
.اينو بگير
Don't be afraid, little man.
.نترس مردِ کوچولو
I love you.
.دوستت دارم
Go on, leave.
.برو، برو
Linito, the man and the kid are escaping.
.لينيتو" مَردِ و بچهه دارن فرار ميکنن"
Let them go.
.بزار برن
The boss says they can leave.
.رئيس گفت که ميتونن برن
Shut the fucking door!
!اون درِ لعنتي رو ببند
Lino wants you in your room.
.لينو" تو اتاقت کارت داره"
General Duarte, in today's press conference...
...ژنرال "دوارته" در کنفرانس مطبوعاتي امروز
... gave a full report on the attack against the criminal group La Estrella.
گزارشِ کاملي در ارتباط با حمله... .عليه گروه جنايتکار "لا اِسترلا" ارائه کرد
Something that can only be classified as a lucky hit.
اتفاقي که تنها ميشه بعنوان .حمله اي با شانس و اقبال ازش نام برد
We've captured most members of the criminal group.
ما بيشتر اعضاي اين گروهِ .جنايتکار رو دستگير کرديم
We've taken most of their weapons and ammo...
بيشتر اسلحه ها و مهماتِ اونا رو ...ثبت و ضبط کرديم
... and we expect to have all of them captured before the weekend is over.
و انتظار داريم پيش از اتمامِ آخر هفته... .همه اعضاي اين گروه رو بازداشت کنيم
Shut the door.
.در رو ببند
Take off your robe.
.لباس حمومت رو در بيار
Put some clothes on.
.لباس درست و درمون بپوش
They've tapped our radios.
.اونا مکالمات راديويي ما رو شنود ميکردن
I'm shutting down.
دارم به آخر خط نزديک ميشم
- Give me a holler when we are ready. - You got it.
وقتي آماده بوديم يه ندايي بده - .بروي چشم -
Tío. Keep an eye on Chiquirris.
.تئو" حواست به "چيکوريس" باشه"
I think he might be a rat.
.گمونم اون يه جاسوس باشه
You got it, boss.
.فهميدم رئيس
That's enough.
.کافيه
Turn off the light.
.چراغا رو خاموش کن
Come here.
.بيا اينجا
Lay down here.
.اينجا دراز بکش
Don't move.
.تکون نخور
Be still.
.آروم بمون
Hands up.
.دستات رو ببر بالا
Put these on.
اينو پات کن
Tío. We're ready.
.تئو". ما آماده ايم"
Call Jimmy, we'll need three cases of bullets.
به "جيمي" زنگ بزن .سه جعبه فشنگ لازم داريم
Canelita. You're gonna bring back a truck.
کانليتا". تو بايد" .يه ماشين رو بايد برگردوني
When you cross the border, go under the bridge.
وقتي از مرز گذشتي .برو روي پل
I'll be waiting for you there.
.اونجا منتظرتم
Take a good look at these monkeys. Tell me who took your phone.
به اين ميمونا خوب نگاه کن .و بگو کي تلفنت رو ازت گرفت
This one.
.اون يکي
Tío, we know who did it. Call the taxi.
.تيو" ميدونم کار کي بوده" .يه تاکسي بگير
The gringo is waiting for her.
.اون خارجي (آمريکايي) منتظر دخترس
Okay, we're here.
.خيلي خب، رسيديم
If they catch you with the money, tell them you don't know me.
اگه با پولا گرفتنت .بهشون بگو که منو نميشناسي
I have a family to feed.
.من هفت سر عائله دارم
- Where are you heading? - To San Diego.
کجا داري ميري؟ - "به "سن ديگو -
- Who sent you? - Nobody.
کي تو رو فرستاده؟ - .هيشکي -
- What's the purpose of your visit? - I'm going shopping.
هدفت از اين سفر چيه؟ - .دارم ميرم خريد -
I need your passport.
.گذرنامه ات رو بده بهم
Laura Guerrero, LG08714678.
"لورا گوئررو" LG08714678
- She's clear, let her through. - Let her through.
.اون موردي نداره، بزارين رد بشه - .بزارين رد شه -
Let her through, move the truck.
.بزارين رد بشه، ماشين رو جابجا کن
The chick got through.
.اين جيگر رو بزارين رد بشه
Your passport.
.گذرنامه ات
Laura Guerrero, LG0871...
"لورا گوئررو" ...LG0871
She's clean, let her through.
.اون موردي نداره، بزارين رد بشه .بزار رد شه
- Understand? - Yes.
فهميدي؟ - .آره -
Stop, stop!
!وايسا، وايسا
Hurry, they're hitting us hard!
!زود باش، اونا بدجوري دارن بهمون تيراندازي ميکنن
Go get Canelita!
!برو پيشِ "کانليتا"
- Get down! - Go get Canelita and the ammo!
!بخواب رو زمين - !برو پيشِ "کانليتا" و مهمات -
Get down, get down!
بخواب رو زمين !بخواب رو زمين
Get her out, get her out!
سرشو پايين نگه دار !بيارش بيرون
Get the girl inside, cover her!
.دختر رو ببر داخل !پوششش بده
Let's get out of here!
!بزن بريم از اينجا
Go, go, go!
!برو، برو، برو
Hop on!
!بندازش
What did the gringo tell you?
اون خارجي بهت چي گفت؟
Kike Camara is in Tijuana.
کيکي کامارا" تو منطقه "تيخوانا"س"
What else?
ديگه چي؟
He's under the name of Orlando Gomez.
"اونجا بهش ميگن "ارلاندو گومز
- That's it? - Nothing else.
فقط همين؟ - آره -
That gringo motherfucker.
.اون خارجي مادر بخطا
Okay, let's go.
.خيلي خب، بريم
Get down, get down.
.برو پايين. برو پايين
Get in.
.سوار شو
We're almost there.
.تقريبا رسيديم ديگه
Linito, they said it was the general who screwed us over.
لينيتو" اونا ميگن کار ژنرال بوده" .که دهنمون رو اونجا سرويس کرده
Okay, Pollo.
"خيلي خب "پولو
Sniff this, Canelita.
"اينو بو بکش "کانليتا
There's been a change in the order of the girls.
يه تغييري تو ليستِ دخترا رخ داده
Here she is, Laura Guerrero.
اين "لورا گوئررو"ـه
She goes on right after Jessica.
.بعدِ "جسيکا" نوبت اونه
There's a change in the swimsuit lineup.
يه تغييري توي صف دخترهاي .لباس شنا پوش رخ داده
Listen to me, goddamn it. Frank, get her ready.
.بهم گوش کن، لعنتي .فرانک" آماده اش کن"
Right now!
!همين الان
Jessica, it's time.
.جسيکا" وقتشه"
Just leave it, come on.
.بيخيالش شو، زود باش
Coming up next, our beautiful candidates will participate...
نفرِ بعدي کانديداي زيباي ما
...in the swimsuit portion of the competition.
که با لباس شنا... .در رقابت ها شرکت کرده
From Mexicali, she studies botany.
از شمالِ مکزيک .اون گياه شناسي ميخونه
She dreams of traveling the world while helping to save the planet.
آرزو داره که به سراسر دنيا سفر کنه .و به نجات سياره زمين کمک کنه
A round of applause for Miss Jessica Verduzco.
"براي دوشيزه "جسيکا وردوزکو .يک کفِ مرتب بزنيد
Ambassador of this great city. She studies pedagogy.
.سفيرِ اين شهرِ بزرگ .در رشته تعليم و پرورش کودکان تحصيل ميکنه
Her dream is to help her brother earn a college degree.
روياي اون اينه که به برادرش کمک کنه .تا به درجات بالاي دانشگاهي برسه
A round of applause for Laura Guerrero.
به افتخار "لورا گوئررو" دست .قشنگِ رو بزنيد
Good evening. Baja California is one of the most beautiful states in this country.
عصر بخير. منطقه "باخا کاليفرنيا" يکي از .زيباترين ايالتهاي اين کشور هست
But oftentimes, it's only known for its defects.
اما بيشتر اوقات فقط براي .عيبهاش شناخته شده
I believe that with education, tolerance and respect...
من اعتقاد دارم که با تعليم و آموزش ...بردباري و احترام
...we can show everybody that this is a place full of light.
ميتونيم به همگان نشون بديم... .که اينجا شهري پر از نور و روشناييه
Absolutely, this place is full of light.
.البته که اين شهر پر از زيباييه
Let's hear it for Jessica Verduzco. Thank you very much.
. صحبتهاي "جسيکا وردوزکو" رو شنيديم .خيلي ممنون و مچکر
A stunning young lady. Her presence lights up the stage...
.يک خانومِ ماهِ جوان ..."حضورش روي صحنه انتخاب دختر شايسته "باخا کاليفرنيا
...the Miss Baja California stage.
.اينجا رو منور کرده...
And now, Laura Guerrero.
"و حالا "لورا گوئررو
A 23-year-old from Tijuana.
"يک دختر 23 ساله اهلِ "تيخوانا
And here she comes, Laura Guerrero.
.و حالا  "لورا گوئررو" داره مياد
How are you this evening?
امروز عصر حالت چطوره؟
Fine, thank you.
.خوبم، ممنون
Laura, tell me, what do you desire most, wealth or fame?
لورا" بهم بگو کدوم يکي رو ميپسندي" شهرت يا ثروت؟
I believe that...
...بنظر من
I'm sorry.
.معذرت ميخوام
Overcome by emotion. She fills the stage with her sensitivity, Laura Guerrero.
بايد بر احساساتش غلبه کنه. صحنه .مملو از ظرافت "لورا گوئررو" شده
She enhances this stage with her beauty.
با زيبايي خودش ارزش اين .سکو و صحنه رو افزايش داده
A big round of applause for Laura Guerrero, please...
خواهش ميکنم "لورا گوئررو" رو ...تشويق کنين
...who leaves us filled with emotion.
.که همه ما رو احساساتي کرده...
And our pageant continues...
...و مراسمِ ما همچنان ادامه خواهد داشت
Arturo.
"آرتورو"
Are you okay?
حالت خوبه؟
Where are you?
کجايي؟
Okay, girls, gather together.
.خيلي خب دخترا، همتون جمع شيد
- Don't go to the house, okay? - It's prayer time, come.
خونه نرو باشه؟ - .وقت دعاست، بياين -
No, I'm fine.
.نه،من خوبم
Yes.
.بله
The time has come.
.الان وقتشه
I'll call you later.
.بعدا بهت زنگ ميزنم
- Later. - Think about it.
.تا بعد - .بهش فکر کن -
Take care.
.مراقب خودت باش
How many bridges you had to cross to get here.
چند تا خان رو رد کردين .تا به اينجا رسيدين
You have the external beauty. Now take a look inside...
.شما بينهايت زيبا هستين ...حالا يه نگاهي به درون خودتون بندازين
...and surprise yourself.
.و خودتون رو غافلگير کنين...
Seize every moment.
.همه لحظات رو مالِ خودتون کنين
As you know, this is the most beautiful day of your life.
همونطوري که ميدونين اين يکي .از زيباترين روزهاي زندگيتونه
What's our motto?
شعار ما چيه؟
Viva Miss Baja California!
"زنده باد دختر شايسته "باخا کاليفرنيا
Let's go. Let's go.
.بريم. بريم
Coming up, we will announce the winner of Miss Baja California.
"تا لحطاتي ديگر دختر شايسته "باخا کاليفرنيا .رو معرفي خواهيم کرد
Miranda Cortina, from Ensenada, Baja California.
"ميراندا کورتينا" "از منطقه "اِنسِنادا، باخا کاليفرنيا
A big round of applause for Miranda...
..."يه کفِ مرتب به افتخارِ "ميراندا
...who at this moment is receiving a beautiful bouquet of flowers.
که در اين لحظه يک سبدِ گل... .رو دريافت ميکنه
Now, one of these two beauties before us will be the new Miss Baja California.
حالا، يکي از اين دو زيبا روي ِ ما .بعنوان دختر شايسته "باخا کاليفرنيا" انتخاب خواهد شد
Please listen carefully.
.لطفا با دقت گوش کنين
I'm going to say the name of the Miss Baja California runner-up.
ميخوام نام نفر دوم مراسمِ .دختر شايسته "باخا کاليفرنيا" رو اعلام کنم
And the second-place winner is...
...و جايگاه دوم تعلق ميگيره به
...Jessica Verduzco from Mexicali, Baja California.
"جسيکا وِردوزکو" از "شمال مکزيک"... "باخا کاليفرنيا"
A big round of applause for her.
.يه تشويق جانانه براي اون بکنين
That makes this beautiful young lady...
...اين باعث ميشه تا اين دختر خانم زيبا
...Laura Guerrero from Tijuana, Baja California, our new beauty queen.
"لورا گوئررو" از "تيخوانا"... .باخا کاليفرنيا" ملکه جديدِ زيبايي ما باشه"
And now she's going to be crowned by the former Miss Baja California queen.
و در اين لحظه قرار است که تاج وي .توسط ملکه زيبايي سابق بهش اعطا بشه
A big round of applause for her.
.يه کفِ مرتب به افتخارش
She's now receiving her official beauty queen sash.
در اين لحظه وي حمايل ويژه .ملکه زيبايي رو دريافت ميکنه
Those are the drums of our band La Furia, who delight us with their music.
اينهم صداي "درامِ" گروه "لا فورا" هست .که با موزيکشون ما رو کلي شاد ميکنن
Our new beauty queen, Laura Guerrero...
..."ملکه زيبايي جديدِ ما "لورا گوئررو
...is being presented with the most beautiful bouquet of flowers by this young man.
اين مَردِ جوان  اين سبدِ گلِ... .بسيار زيبا رو بهش تقديم ميکنه
And let's hear that round of applause for all of our...
...و بياين صداي تشويق رو براي همه
...Miss Baja California contestants.
.شرکت کننده هاي اين مسابقه بشنويم
Laura Guerrero...
..."لورا گوئررو"
...our new beauty queen, Miss Baja California!
...ملکه زيبايي جديدِ ما... !"دختر شايسته "باخا کاليفرنيا
Let's hear that applause. Let's hear it for her one more time.
.به افتخارش .يه بار ديگه بزنين اين دست قشنگه رو
Laura, you meet the press in 10 minutes. Laura?
لورا" ده دقيقه ديگه با رسانه ها" بايد حرف بزني، "لورا"؟
Why did you run away? Didn't you want to be a queen?
چرا داشتي فرار ميکردي؟ مگه نميخواستي ملکه زيبايي بشي؟
Yeah, but not like that.
.آره اما اينجوري نه
Well, that's the luck of the draw. If you wanna leave, then get the hell out.
خب، شانس درِ خونه ات رو زد اگه ميخواي يه هوايي بخوري ميتوني بري
But you can't come back here again. You can't go to your house...
.منتها دوباره نميتوني برگردي اينجا ...نميتوني بري خونه ات
...or talk to anybody you know.
يا با کسايي که ميشناسيشون... حرف نزن
Take this money.
.اين پول رو بگير
Walk straight for a couple of hours and you'll hit something.
يه چند ساعتي با خودت خلوت کن .و يه چيزي بخور
Go.
.برو
Take off your clothes.
.لباسات رو در بيار
Time for your interview, man.
.وقت مصاحبه ات رسيده مَرد
Name?
اسم؟
Kike Camara.
"کيکه کامارا"
Name.
.اسم
Enrique Camara.
"انريکه کامارا"
Who do you work for?
واسه کي کار ميکني؟
For the DEA.
.براي اداره مبارزه با مواد مخدر آمريکا
Here in Mexico, who do you operate with?
...اينجا تو مکزيک با کي تو عمليات همکاري ميکني؟
What do you have to say to those motherfuckers that work with you?
چرا بايد به اون مادر سگها بگي که با تو کار کنن؟
They know what they have to do.
.اونا کارشون رو بلدن
Why do you come here to fuck everything up?
چرا اومدي اينجا تا همه چيو بهم بريزي؟
You should've stayed in your country, motherfucker.
تو بايد تو همون کشورِت .ميموندي پدر سوخته
- Did you find something? - Nothing.
چيزي پيدا نکردي؟ - .نه -
- Keep going. - Just police reports, from the gringos.
.ادامه بده - .فقط گزارشهاي پليس از طرف يه خارجي -
Wear this.
.اينو بپوش
Tie it off!
!معلق نگهش دارين
Who's in to go to the hotel?
کي پايه اس بريم هتل؟
I don't think so, it's too dangerous.
.فک نميکنم کسي باشه .خيلي خطرناکه
Come on, Lino. It's too risky.
"يالا "لينو .به ريسکش نميارزه
We'll be in and out.
.بايد بريم و بيام
I don't know, boss.
.نميدونم رئيس
You monkeys.
.شما ميمونا
Where's the crown?
تاج کجاس؟
Get in the truck.
.ببرش تو ماشين
Check the gear, I want every gun working.
وسايل رو چک بکن .ميخوام همه اسلحه ها سالم باشن
Okay, fuckers. Who's in?
خيلي خب عوضيا. کي پايه اس؟
Forty grand for each one of you for this one.
چهل هزار دلار براي هر کدوم از شماها .که تو اينکار باشين
Come on, guys, we're fearless.
.يالا بچه ها، ما شجاعيما
Come on. Get in.
.يالا. سوار شو
Get in.
.سوار شو
It's crawling with cops, we have to go around.
.پليسا از سر و کولِ اينجا بالا ميرن .بايد يه دوري بزنيم
Okay, you know what to do.
.خيلي خب، ميدوني که بايد چيکار کني
I'm here, partner. Talk to me.
.من اينجام همکار. باهام حرف بزن
I'm sending you three cars for backup.
من اين ماشينا رو واسه .پشتيباني فرستادم
We're on our way.
.ما تو راهيم
How's it looking?
چطور بنظر مياد؟
How's it looking, Pollo?
.ما توراهيم اوضاع چطوره "پولو"؟
He's here with his men.
.با آدماش اينجاس
How many are there?
چند تا هستن؟
There are lots of pigs and about eight trucks.
خيلي خوک اينجاس .و 8 تا هم ماشين هست
Okay.
.خيلي خب
You're going to have breakfast with the general. They're going to introduce him...
.قراره با ژنرال صحبونه بخوري ...اونا قرار تو رو بهش
...to you. You're gonna flirt with him.
معرفي کنن. قراره... .باهاش لاس بزني
Later, he'll ask you to go to his room.
بعدا، اون ازت ميخواد .که باهاش بري تو اتاقش
Or he'll invite you somewhere else.
.و يا به يه جايِ ديگه دعوتت ميکنه
What if he doesn't invite me?
اگه دعوتم نکرد چي؟
Just flirt with him and forget about the rest.
فقط باهاش لاس بزن .و بقيه چيزا رو فراموش کن
You know what we need.
.ميدوني که چي ميخوايم
We want to know when you're alone with him.
بايد بدونيم کي .باهاش تنهايي
Take this. We'll call you when you're inside. Don't hang up.
.اينو بگير. بهت وقتي اون داخل هستي زنگ ميزنيم .تلفن رو قطع نکن
Stay on the line.
.روي خط بمون
Come on, get out. Hurry, hurry.
.يالا، برو، زود باش، يالا
What's the purpose of your visit?
هدفتون از اين سفر چيه؟
My name is Laura Guerrero. I'm here for the Miss Baja event.
.اسم من "لورا گوئررو" هست .من براي مراسم دختر شايسته اينجا اومدم
- Hello, welcome. They're waiting for you. - Hello.
.سلام، خوش اومدين. اونا منتظر شما هستن - سلام -
- Where's the crown? - Thank you.
تاج کجاست؟ - .ممنونم -
Where were you?
کجا بودي؟
Why did you disappear? Smile.
.چرا غيبت زد؟ لبخند بزن
Don Salomón.
"دون "سالمن
General, how are you?
ژنرال احوالِ شما؟
- Luisa, it's a pleasure seeing you again. - Laura, come.
.لوئيزا" مايه خرسنديِ که دوباره ميبينمت" - .لورا" بيا" -
I want you to meet Laura, the new Miss Baja California.
ميخوام با "لورا" آشنا بشيد .دختر شايسته جديد "باخا کاليفرنيا"ست
She was crowned yesterday.
.ديروز تاجگذاري کرد
Freshly crowned, and I must say she has a nice appearance.
تازه تاجگذاري کرده و بايد عرض کنم .که واقعا ظاهرِ زيبايي داره
I'm at your service, general.
.در خدمتم ژنرال
Take a seat, have a drink with us.
.بفرماييد بنشينيد، باهامون چيزي بنوشيد
Thank you, very kind of you, but I have to return to my table.
ممنون، نظر لطفِ شماست .اما بايد برگردم سرِ ميزِ خودم
She's a hottie, general.
.اون واقعا جذابه ژنرال
- Look, you made the front page. - You look good in the picture.
.ببين رفتي رو صفحه اول روزنامه ها - .تو عکسها خوب ميوفتيا -
What time is the interview?
مصاحبه ساعت چنده؟
Four o'clock p.m., but we have to arrive earlier for makeup.
چهار بعد از ظهر اما بايد براي گريم .زودتر بريم
- Miss, from the general. - Thank you.
.دوشيزه از طرفِ ژنراله - .ممنونم -
Beauty Queen Overnight
ملکه زيبايي مسابقه (تيترِ روزنامه)
I'm going to give you this phone. Carry it at all times.
من بهت اين عکس رو ميدم .تا واسه هميشه نگهش داري
You can't disappear like you did yesterday.
نميتوني ديگه مثه ديروز .غيبت بزنه
You caused a lot of problems with the interviews.
مصاحبه نکردنت باعثِ .کلي دردسر شده
And you have to smile more often.
.و بايد بيشتر لبخند بزني
What are the secretaries from the mayor's office doing here?
منشيِ شهردار اينجا چيکار ميکنه؟
Excuse me.
.معذرت ميخوام
Bodies left at the Embassy identified
جنازه هاي رها شده .روبروي سفارت شناسايي شدند
Yes.
.بله
I'm Laura Guerrero. I'm here to see General Duarte.
من "لورا گوئررو" هستم .اومدم اينجا تا ژنرال "دوارته" رو ببينم
I have a Laura Guerrero here to see the general.
لورا گوئررو" همراهِ منه" .تا ژنرال رو ببينه
Let her through.
.بزار بياد داخل
Go ahead.
.بفرما
Please.
.خواهش ميکنم
- Look, it's that blind guy. - What blind guy?
ببين، اين همون مَرد کورَس؟ - کدوم مَردِ کور؟ -
The one that sings.
.هموني که ميخونه
Sir, Miss Laura is here.
.قربان، دوشيزه "لورا" اينجاست
All right.
.خيلي خب
Come in, please.
.بفرماييد داخل، خواهش ميکنم
You have to get it together.
بايد دوستانه فراهمش کني
What's important is that you send me some men that can stay with me.
مساله اي که مهمه اينه که بايد چند نفر رو بفرستي پيشم بمونن
Make yourself a drink. Start getting undressed.
.براي خودت نوشيدني بريز .لباسات رو هم کم کم در بيار
That incident with the gringo has caused me serious problems.
اون اتفاقي که براي خارجيِ افتاد کلي مشکل واسم درست کردش
I have to issue a report very soon.
.بايد خيلي زود مساله رو گزارش کنم
They're gonna kill you.
اونا ميخوان تو رو بکُشن
They're going to kill you. They're listening to us.
.اونا ميکُشنت .الانم دارن به حرفاي ما گوش ميدن
Oh, yeah, baby, that's it.
.اُه، آره عزيزم. همينه
Open your legs.
.پاهات رو باز کن
Stay calm.
.آروم باش
Go, go, go.
.برو، برو، برو
Close off the area. Let's go, let's go.
.منطقه رو ببندين. بريم، بريم
Make sure there's no one left in the rooms.
.مطمئن شيد که کسي تو اتاقها نمونده باشه
They're all yours. We're all set.
همه چي در اختيار شماست حاضر و آماده
She's under the bed, get her out.
.اون زير تخته، بيارينش بيرون
Bring the girl over here.
.دخترِ رو بيارين اينجا
Fuck her up!
!سرويسش کنين
Ready?
آماده اي؟
- Sir, can I please make a phone call? - Sorry, babe, we're about to start.
قربان، ميشه يه زنگ بزنم؟ - .متاسفم عزيزم، تازه داريم کارمونو شروع ميکنيم -
Let's go.
.بريم
Keep your head up, babe.
.سرتو بالا نگه دار عزيزم
The spokesperson for the attorney general will give us a detailed report...
...سخنگوي دادستانِ کل جزيياتي از گزارش
...of yesterday's operation.
.عمليات ديروز در اختيار ما گذاشت
In a joint effort...
...در يک تلاش تيمي
...federal, state and local police...
...ماموران فدرال، پليس ايالتي و محلي....
...fought and defeated the criminal group known as La Estrella.
.گروهِ جنايتکارِ "لا اِسترلا" منهدم و متلاشي شد...
In this operation, the lives of Captain Agustin Robles...
در اين عمليات،  کاپيتان ..."آگوستين روبلس"
...and eight state policemen were lost...
...و هشت پليسِ ايالتي ديگر
...along with those of eight criminals.
.همراه هشت جنايتکار کشته شدند...
Among them, the leader of the group, Chalino Valdez, a.k.a. Lino...
در ميان اين جنايتکاران، سردسته گروه ..."چالينو والدز" ملقب به "لينو"
...and one of his personal bodyguards Lorenzo San Martin, a.k.a. Tío.
و يکي از محافظين شخصي اش... .لورنزو سن مارتين" ملقب به "تيو" نيز به چشم ميخورد"
Also captured during the operation...
...همچنين در طي اين عمليات
...Laura Guerrero, formerly Miss Baja California...
"لورا گوئررو"... ..."بانوي "باخا کاليفرنيا
...allegedly responsible for parking the vehicle at the embassy...
که ظاهرا مسئولِ پارکِ... ...اتومبيل در جلوي سفارت
...containing the bodies of Commander Fernandez, Agent Raymond Bell...
"که شامل جنازه هاي فرمانده "هرناندز... ..."مامور "ريموند بِل
...as well as Azucena Ramos, civilian.
و يک شهروند "آزوسنا راموس" بوده است... .دستگير شده
I'm sorry.
.معذرت ميخوام
Forgive me.
.منو ببخش
The stunning young lady on your screen, who was crowned Miss Baja California...
اين دختر زيبا روي رو صفحه تلويزيون ...کسي است که بعنوان ملکه زيبايي انتخاب شده بود
... has just been arrested.
.و به تازگي دستگير شده...
Her name is Laura Guerrero, she's from Tijuana, Baja California.
اسمِ وي "لورا گوئررو" است .وي اهلِ "تيخوانا باخا کاليفرنيا"ست
They found her in possession of weapons, over 1000 cartons of ammo...
مامورين پليس او را همراه اسلحه ها ... و بيش از 1000 کارتن فشنگ
... and approximately $100,000.
و نزديک به 100 هزار دلار پول... .پيدا کرده اند
The young lady is being linked to the criminal group La Estrella...
اين خانمِ جوان در ارتباط با گروهِ ...جنايتکارِ "لا استرِلا" بوده
... who were captured during an operation by federal and state police...
که در حين عمليات مامورين فدرال... ...و پليس ايالتي دستگير شده
... where there was an attempt against General Salomón Duarte.
جايي که سوء قصدي به جان... .ژنرال "سالمون دوارته" در جريان بوده
She was the only woman captured amongst the powerful criminal group.
وي تنها زني است که در ميان .دستگير شدگان اين گروه جاني قدرتمند بوده
I repeat, her name is Laura Guerrero.
.تکرار ميکنم اسمِ وي "لورا گوئررو"ست
On the phone with us is Luisa Janes, pageant coordinator.
"پاي تلفن، همراهِ ما "لوئيزا جونز .هماهنگ کننده مراسم دختر شايسته است
Thank you for letting me voice my opinion.
ممنونم از اين فرصتي که بهم داديد .تا نظراتم را عنوان کنم
This is definitely a very delicate subject and a real shame.
اين حقيقتا موضوعي خيلي حساس .و مايه شرمساري است
The actions of girls like her are a real embarrassment to Mexico.
فعاليت دختراني نظير وي .مايه خجالت کشور مکزيک است
The Miss Baja California pageant condemns these actions.
مسئولين مراسم انتخاب دخترِ شايسته .شديدا اين اعمال رو محکوم ميکنند
What's going on?
چه خبره؟
Let me go!
!ولم کن
THE MEXICAN DRUG WAR HAS CAUSED THE DEATHS...
جنگِ مواد مخدر مکزيکي ها ...باعثِ مرگِ
...OF OVER 36,000 PEOPLE BETWEEN 2006 AND 2011.
بيش از 36 هزار نفر... .بين سالهاي 2006 تا 2011 شده است
IN MEXICO ALONE...
...تنها در کشور مکزيک
...DRUG TRAFFICKING GENERATES 25 BILLION DOLLARS A YEAR.
قاچاق مواد مخدر سالانه... سي و شش ميليارد دلار درآمد دارد